Jesus Molina

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} $\textcircled{$\otimes$} & (415) \ 685\text{-}3049 \\ & & cloud@jesusmolina.com \\ \begin{tabular}{ll} \o & http://www.jesusmolina.com \\ \end{tabular}$

Profile

Consultant with eight years of experience in standardization committees

Experience with virtualization technologies and cloud management

Inventor with several patents in cloud computing, computer security and E-commerce

12 years of computer security experience, including authentication protocols, biometrics, trusted computing and cryptography

Proven Ability to direct complex projects from concept to fully operational status

Education

2007 **PhD in Electrical and Computer Engineering**, *University of Maryland College Park*.

2001 M.Sc. in Electrical and Computer Engineering (with thesis), University of Maryland College Park.

1999 **B.S. Degree in Electrical Engineering**, *UNIVERISTITAT POLITECNICA CATALUNYA*, *Barcelona*, *Spain*.

Services

Contributor to the OASIS TOSCA for cloud orchestration

Contributor to the Big Data Working Group at the Cloud Security Alliance

Contributor and Evaluator of the Open Source DeltaCloud project

Guest editor for the IEEE Security and privacy special issue Development of Authentication Technologies (January/February 2012)

National Science Foundation Panelist

Contributor at DMTF Cloud Management Working group

Contributor at the Cyber Security Coordination Task Force (Now SGIP-CSWW)

Formed board member and chair at the Trusted Computing Group

Employment

Present Jesus Molina Consulting, Owner.

Assist standardization efforts, both technically and strategically

2007-2011 Fujitsu Laboratories of America., Member of Research Staff.

- O Collaborated with standardization committees in the fields of authentication and trusted computing
- O Oversee research projects on the fields of security, embedded systems and virtualization
- O Developed new technologies and intellectual property in emerging technologies
- O Published research at academic and professional conferences and journals

2002-2007 Fujitsu Laboratories of America., Research Intern.

- O Lead and maintained software for cryptographic module (TPM) emulation
- O Ported and extended on-site TPM-emulator for FRV Fujitsu based IP phone.

- 2006-2008 Center for Risk and Reliability, Research Assistant.
 - O Developed an evaluation method for intrusion detection systems
 - O Deployed high assurance honeypots to monitor attacker actions in filesystems
- 2001-2006 Maryland Information Systems Security Lab, Research Assistant.
 - O Created a secure embedded filesystem integrity checker and a patent pending embedded memory integrity checker (Komoku and Copilot)

Recent Talks

Panelist DAC 2011 Hackers and Attackers: How Safe is Your Embedded Design? Presented attacks to smart meters

Speaker Cloud Security Alliance congress 2010 Leveraging Trusted Technologies to Secure the Cloud

Speaker Secure Cloud 2010 Practical Applications of Trusted Computing in the Cloud Speaker Storage Developers Conference 2010 Designing Secure Storage for the Cloud Publications

- **Z. Song, J. Molina, and C. Strong**. Trusted Anonymous Execution: A Model to Raise Trust in Cloud. In Proceedings of the 2010 Ninth International Conference on Grid and Cloud Computing (GCC '10) [pdf] [bibtex]
- Chow, R.; Jakobsson, M.; Niu, Y.; Shi, E.; Molina, J.; Masuoka, R.; Song, Z. Authentication in the clouds: a framework and its application to mobile users. ACM Cloud Computing Security Workshop (CCSW); 2010 [pdf] [bibtex]
- R. Chow, P. Golle, M. Jakobsson, E. Shi, J. Staddon, R. Masuoka, and J. Molina. Controlling data in the cloud: outsourcing computation without outsourcing control. In Proceedings of the 2009 ACM workshop on Cloud computing security (CCSW '09) [pdf] [bibtex]

Jesus Molina, "Evaluating Host Intrusion Detection Systems" Ph.D. Thesis, December 2007 [pdf]

J. Molina, Xavier Chorin, M. Cukier. Filesystem Activity Following a SSH Compromise: An Empirical Study of File Sequences. ICISC 2007: 144-155

Jesus Molina, Houcheng Li, Sung Lee, Zhexuan Song. A Mobile Trusted Platform Module (mTPM) Architecture, Workshop on Advances in Trusted Computing, Tokyo, November 2006) [pdf] [bibtex]

- N. L. Petroni, J. Molina, T. Fraser, W. A. Arbaugh. *Copilot: A Coprocessor Based Runtime Integrity Monitor*. 13th Usenix Security Symposium 2004) [pdf] [bibtex]
- **J. Molina, W. Arbaugh**. *Using Independent Auditors as Intrusion Detection Systems*. ICICS 2002: 291-302, December 9-12, 2002 Springer) [pdf] bibtex
- **J. Molina**. Using Independent Auditors for Intrusion Detection Systems, Master's Thesis. 2001. Advisor William A. Arbaugh [pdf] [bibtex]